

Raymond Ortiz

A Biomedical Engineer with five years of professional experience, specializing in the i nstallation, configuration, and maintenance of medical equipment maintenance. A proven track record of identifying technical solutions to equipment defects in high-volume hospital environments.

Professional Experience

Biomedical Engineer

Detroit Medical Center, Detroit, MI | May 2019 - Present

- Deliver technical support for medical equipment for a high volume hospital with a
 6:1 patient ratio, including EKGs, surgical devices, dopplers, and dialysis machines
- Implement a new preventative maintenance schedule to prevent risk of equipment failure, improve operational efficiency, and enhance patient flow by 5%
- Provide training to 20+ nursesand medical staff on equipment usage and troubleshooting

Biomedical Engineer

Mercy Hospital, Detroit, MI | October 2017- May 2019

- Executed complex technical implementations for large hospitals, ensured safe and optimal functioning of biomedical devices, and achieved a 94% client satisfaction rate
- Reduced equipment downtime by 15% by providing remedial training to hospital personnel and implementing preventative maintenance procedures

123 W Adams Ave, Detroit, MI 12345 ra ym ondorti2@examp le.com (123)456-7890

Education

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Biomedical Engineering University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI Septem be r 2013 - May 2017

Key Skills

- ♦ Biomedical Equipment
- ♦ Technical Support
- ♦ Preventative Maintenance
- Process I mp rovem e nt
- ♦ Med i ca I Devi ce Safety

Certifications

Biomedical Equipment Technician
 Certification (CBET), May 2017